But I would like, if you want to keep it,
I would take the transcript or copy,
copy it somewhere.
or for all of these sessions.
All right, let's recap. What were we,
what did we talk about on Tuesday?
of putting on the spire.
Yeah, last Tuesday,
one of the things that was major and I
think yesterday also we discussed it was
about integration,
integration with other systems that
that's my
you know,
homework to provide a consolidated map of
our...
Not how, not all,
but also how that we have integrated with
other services or applications.
I have booked a meeting with Esther and
we and also we talked about.
Different pops,
different things of in in this picture
about the platform configuration,
about firmware user management and access
experience. Yeah, we double.
click some of them mainly on the access
integrations, navigation integration,
and about the roles.
I think we talked about the roles mainly
and...
and also feature module capability,
which actually is stretched to yesterday
conversation as well. But yeah,
that's what I remember.
Yeah, so you should be,
you should be so familiar with this space
after we're done discovering, right?
Because that's what we're doing now.
Like I was going to gray it out,
but I'm like, you know what,
by the time you guys are done,
you're going to build it.
So it's going to be there. Yeah,
and then it's a good recap.
We talked about the constraints around
the kind of the RBAC model we have today,
right? So user package equals user group,
you can only have one-to-one.
It is the genesis of all of our problems
related to access.
And then the other world of problems is
resources. Now you know between these two,
it's the burden of our pains for the last
five years.
Well, well, you know,
we got into the platform integrations and
while you speak to Esther, Ali,
what I think Candi,
what we should do is actually give Ali an
explicit list of all the apps that he
should look at because I'm not sure,
like I think he needs to guide Esther a
little bit on what to go through.
And, you know, sometimes it's systems,
sometimes it's the actual app itself,
like even though we have secured zone,
you know,
SOMA and GIC are two different
integrations,
and then the rest of the apps are yet
different integrations, right?
So can you help Ali just kind of have
that list to go through with Esther?
We'll give you the app list, Ali,
because you're not going to be able to
tell, and then Esther might be like,
what are you asking me, right?
As you go through that, and Kevin,
this is for Ali to help map all the
different integration implementations,
despite having a standard,
none of the implementations were standard,
and there's nuances to even kind of like
what we call a tier one integration.
So we can document it,
we'll bring it back into one of these KT
sessions,
and then we'll review your findings
together.
Because to answer your full question
around the trade-offs, Ali,
I think you need to understand that and
what was the thought process at the time
of these integrations?
And is it worth actually,
some of them is it actually even worth
correcting? Right.
So we'll park that one.
I think we also got a little bit into the
firm management last time. So I think,
I don't know,
Yes.
I can't remember what you joined and what
you didn't join, but last two sessions,
what I wanted to do is to do an knowledge
transfer on all the product capabilities
of platform management.
Right,
so this should be a map of everything
that Ali should be overseeing from a
capability evolution perspective.
And a big part of this conversation,
because you can look at something at face
value,
but you wouldn't know the nuances of the
crazy decisions that we've made in the
past.
I think a lot of the conversations around
the crazy decisions we made in the past.
So we got to,
I think we got to firm management,
we got to firm activation,
we talked about the relationship between
And.
firm 360 to compass, right?
And then we talked about the fact that we
don't have firm,
we have firm activation and the active
activation allows you to
assign users to it,
but we decided not to do firm
deactivation. In fact,
we are not even sure if there was such a
thing as firm deactivation.
Candi was going to confirm for us, right?
If something gets disabled in Firm 360,
what happens?
I don't know if Candi even got the answer
to that yet.
Is it gonna come from from 360?
Little question mark. Do you remember?
Oh, I forgot. Yeah, I'll check it. Yeah.
But we, on campus,
we don't have that firm deactivation
No.
capability. Yeah.
So, so, so I graded out,
and then I know I'll leave you had kind
of a back and forth of, well,
why didn't we?
What's the value at the time, right? So,
you know, it really,
I don't think there's a very clear...
path that we defined for what we get from
Firm 360 and the lifecycle management of
that firm and what should be encompassed.
I don't actually think we talked about it
at all. It was very much a, oh,
if there's a status in Firm 360,
I guess we'll take it.
But we won't take it under certain
Yeah.
scenarios. As you can see, the firm that..
.
Paul's onboarding this week.
It's active in Firm 360,
but disabled on Compass,
but that signifies a new firm.
It's not super clear that that's the case,
right? So it was,
I think there was an implementation at
the time.
MF.
It serves the needs today,
but it could cause a little bit of
confusion.
And then so that's why deactivation,
same same thing. It kind of works,
so we just.
Sorry, Penny,
are we looking at the status of the firm
from Firm 360 as our kind of indicator of
whether it's active or not?
I can't tell you for sure.
I think for now,
one of the thing is we will only filter
Okay.
row when we load the firm list.
We will only select the active firm.
And unless if they change the name,
change the Oracle ranges,
it will be updated in campus the next day.
Yeah, the cut off time is a bit
OK.
weird,
so it would sounds like it's almost t + 2.
Yeah,
because the job run the night after and
something like that,
I can unpack that for you.
But then the other question is if the
firm's already active in campus and
somehow it becomes inactive in firm 360.
Yeah.
Literally,
the firm will not come through the the
the file we we're trying to load from
Firm 360,
Yeah.
but I'm not sure does it do anything
because the firm is now missing. Yeah,
Yeah, that's what I'm wondering. Yeah.
so that's I'm asking the team to check.
I I think that's that was a.
Okay.
requirement to say in such cases we
should disable the firm.
But then there would be some complication
because if the firm already have some
user,
we have to deactivate the user and so on
and so forth.
So there's a chance we didn't do that.
But I am asking Sasha to double check for
me.
So let's find out and let's find out if
it's an issue,
because if there's already existing
processes to off-board users anyway of
the firm when they leave,
which doesn't actually happen too often,
then that's really the main risk you're
managing is the firm's users' ability to
still access accounts,
even though the firm is no longer with us.
But whether the actual firm off-boarding
needs to come into play in full force,
there's a reason why we never addressed
it.
It wasn't a really critical requirement,
right? It's the firm can live on.
Chances are you need access to those
accounts anyway, as Candi was saying,
Yeah.
and you know, right? So
Yeah, I remember now. Yeah,
we talk about because we have to keep the
Yeah, it's not, yeah.
firm alive.
So then some headquarter users,
they can still access their accounts.
Yeah. So maybe it is intentional.
We're not disabling the firm. Yeah.
Either other case,
the use case is a little bit fuzzy.
We never invested time into it.
So leave it gray for now. You know what?
How do you typically find out about
capability gaps more often than not, Ali,
on things that we took shortcuts on is
somebody will scream or there might be an
issue and it becomes a critical issue.
and you will fix it for these residual
decisions. Like big pieces,
like multi-firm, we know that in advance,
like we know that it's an issue.
We know it needs to be supported.
There's plenty of evidence suggesting
that. But for these smaller features,
when it comes to enhancements or what
have you not,
unless you hear a lot of noise,
Typically, we just leave it alone,
as long as the operating procedures are
clear and we're managing the risk
operationally,
'cause in platform management,
you're dealing with a lot of that is
around kind of access and security risks.
Yeah,
I think one of the things that we
discussed, it was about the user journey,
which starts from Firm 360 and then comes
to a compass and other systems.
I think these two systems are not
integrated.
At all,
every every every data movement is
Yeah.
offline is through a manual process,
and one of the things we discuss about
the loosely integration of these two,
you know, applications or...
Platforms, and even I was thinking of,
you know, making one, you know,
because when we,
I understand that you know,
Firm 360 is by Ray's team and they do it
for other purposes, such as...
Billing, you know, other other stuffs,
but which is more internal use rather
than external use. But yeah,
that's something that came to my mind,
but it's not for now, for in discussion,
but
Yeah.
In terms of the data exchange,
I think there are many areas that can be
improved, which I think we encompass,
we pass data to them manually for the
billing reconciliation,
for billing calculation. At the same time,
They pass the data for in the compass for
registering firms. So yeah,
I think there are good things to improve.
Yeah, I think so. And, like I said,
it's it'll this this goes in is an area
that one go will go into your backlog,
like the the data the data sync works now,
but I think that need will change as you
think about managing subscriptions in
both places.
Does it need to be more timely?
Right, does it need to be,
as if something gets elected over there,
Yeah.
it should be over here,
or actually do I configure it over here
and then put it over there?
That's a discussion you guys need to have
with Ray on what's the best approach to
maintain integrity of the system.
Because I, you know,
as much as we're saying Firm 360,
it's a sort of truth, a source of truth.
You can define in there,
you can define things in there and make
it the source of truth,
or you can define things else where and
it gets consolidated into a 360 view,
right? In this case, for subscriptions,
it is, it is, as you can see, Ali,
with the feature management and all this
other crap, it's an enforce,
like the platform is there to enforce,
right?
if you have a unreliable source of truth
coming in to apply access controls and
enforcement,
you can very easily break people's
accesses. So that's our,
that would be my main concern going into
the like kind of the multi-firm
discussion or even beyond that multi-firm,
you'll a little bit touch on this because
you need to start
Getting more from Firm 360,
but there will be a time where you can
you gotta ask yourself,
is that which side should the data come
from and how timely does that data need
to be?
Yeah.
And then so we also touched on the firm
hierarchy firm delegation.
That's really kind of like that
multi-firm discussion we have,
the ability to support kind of cross-firm
boundary access from a user.
So we'll park that one for the multi-firm
discussion.
But that's all there is in terms of
managing a firm, right?
You're taking in the firm subscription,
you're implementing it.
You're further configuring certain firm
like settings based on what they want to
see, what they want to see.
We need to manage the full life cycle of
the firm.
Candi will verify if we fully support
that life cycle management on the
deactivation side. And then, you know,
we enforce through the firm management,
the firm relationships that need to exist
in the system for access provisioning of
somebody who needs access to multiple
firms or like other firms data and
features basically.
So we'll get into this more than the
multi-firm.
And we've seen the firm settings by now,
Ali, I don't need to show you again,
right?
No, it's fine, yeah.
Yeah, so limitations,
the activation is one question,
the hierarchy for sure,
that's why we need to work on that next.
And then some usability limitations,
as you saw,
it's just not a very intuitive UI.
The way firm settings are loaded from the
firm packages.
Results in confusing a confusing
experience,
but you saw that with the like the module
grouping, the show and hide,
and the mandatory resources all listed
out, right? So.
Our teams kind of understand,
like Radhika's team specifically,
and Candi understands what that is,
how that works.
Our support team is still pretty confused
about it.
So you may want to solve that either
operationally, more knowledge transfer,
more training,
bring Kushboo and the team to the table,
make them learn.
because we never pushed hard enough for
that. I would say for the most part,
they didn't understand the firm settings.
So I said, Radhika,
you deal with the firm settings because
it's part of the product activation
function anyway for you to understand
firm implementation and configuration.
At some point,
from a troubleshooting perspective,
support still needs to understand.
So there still needs to be that knowledge
transfer before you go into thinking,
you know, Ali, oh,
maybe I need to prioritize those
usability issues because it's still,
it's still an internal tool at the end of
the day, right?
All our internal tools are kind of crap
because they're made for employees.
And as employees,
we're paid to deal with it. So.
Again, this might come up, it might be,
oh my God, so confusing, but okay,
do you want to fix,
do you want to train on how firm settings
work for support?
Or do you want to deal with the lack of
deactivation?
Or do you want to deal with the lack of
full firm synchronization of the
hierarchy?
Do you want to deal with the actual firm?
Like what's more important in the
ecosystem?
Out of all this stuff that's missing so
far, it's probably the firm hierarchy,
right?
And it impacts our clients the most.
But you'll build a list,
you'll figure it out.
I mean, of in your backlog.
Yeah.
Okay,
so I guess we'll move over to user
management.
which by this definition,
we mean user lifecycle management, right?
So I'm hoping, oh, Candi,
I'm hoping this is really straightforward.
But let's see.
So what do we have in user management?
User lifecycle. So the ability to create,
update, and deactivate users. Oh,
I need to edit this.
Pretty important from a, I guess,
from a firm user access control
perspective. Candi,
we don't we don't have to delete our
archive yet, right?
No, we only deactivate.
We don't delete any profile at this point.
So let me show you. So again, Ali,
it's historical. Ideally,
we implemented the full user lifecycle
function, so you can go ahead and,
you know, onboard a user,
set them up through our internal user
settings, or you can go in at any time.
I can go in here.
And I can update a profile.
I think so.
Yeah,
I played here this week with creating
user, uploading, exporting.
Right, yeah, and you can kind of update,
deactivate, right? Pretty straightforward.
Lam.
Once you deactivate the user,
what happens, Candi, when you deactivate?
Profile settings, well, user,
we block login, is that the main,
is that the main?
function of the activation.
Deactivation, several things.
So we keep the profile access proficient,
like all the your role,
your settings intact,
so we're not removing it.
But then you cannot log in for sure.
And, um,
and your profile cannot be changed.
This one, yeah.
So you have to enable the user before you
Yeah, it will look like that.
make any change.
So kind of freezing this user account.
Yeah.
Reason why we have those two steps, Ali,
is between deactivate and this delete
that doesn't actually exist is, you know,
people might not have left the firm.
They might have like, I don't know,
gone on like mat leave or something.
They left for a year.
Firm has a policy to say if you're not
active for a certain amount of time,
you should probably be deactivated,
but they might come back.
One thing,
very important thing to note for that
reason as well is when you try to remove
a user,
because transactions are tied to your
user,
like real transactions in Compass and
outside of Compass,
it's actually pretty important to retain
the integrity of the ID against that
request.
And so this is why we didn't go down the
path of deleting a user yet.
We will have to at some point, if the,
you know,
an active user list becomes thousands and
thousands of users,
it becomes unmanageable, right?
We don't have that problem right now.
But when you go through and think about
user deletion,
you have to think about also, well,
what do you do with all the things that
are actually tied to that user ID?
So if you placed a trade in that user ID,
what do you do with it? Firms, right,
Mhm.
typically have a user tied to a set of R
codes and a set of transactions related
to that.
So if you go and delete a user who gets
the visibility of those transactions,
that's an important consideration.
Kevin can tell you all about that in
servicing as well.
big debacle in the servicing space.
When somebody leaves,
the system behaves a little bit
differently,
and then people actually start losing
visibility of those transactions because
you can't look it up by the user ID,
right?
Or you might not remember what that user
ID is for the person who left,
and you're going to have to go and query
it somehow.
So your interpretation is that when we
delete a user, all the associate, sorry,
Deactivate.
not deactivate,
I'm talking about the future state,
which is delete.
Mhm.
Billing.
Is that the when we delete the object of
the user from the systems?
It means that all the associated data
from orders, from trades,
where where it sits,
it should be deleted or only the data of
the user inside user management.
The,
I think the right way to do it is you
retain who in who managed,
like who did something to that
transaction. So if it's orders,
you need to retain your ID.
You can't get rid of it, right?
Because you need that audit trail of,
Yeah.
because let's say that person left
because it was a disciplinary thing and
Yeah.
now you need to audit all the stuff he
did.
right?
You need that user ID to look it up.
You can't do without it.
I think the problem is, and Candi,
Yeah.
I don't know if this is a real problem or
not,
like it came up as a problem in the past,
I think for trading,
is every app behaves differently when it
comes to retaining that user reference.
And I believe there are some apps,
I don't know if it's all,
where if you remove the user entry in
Furman User Management,
they call FBN UM to pull up the user data.
So like that might break.
I don't know where it breaks.
I don't know if it's still a case,
Yeah.
but we found that case in the past.
So that needs to be resolved or you can,
Yeah, is.
like as a prerequisite before you can
move on to.
thinkable deletion.
Yeah, is the known issue.
And that's also part of the reason we're
not deleting profiles.
I just talked to JP a few days or
yesterday about this one,
because it's Owen, yeah, I mentioned.
that is at least this is how all those
work.
So these are the transactional history.
So someone, as Penny mentioned,
someone placed an order and maybe in the
other system,
they lock it under a user ID.
So it wouldn't lock the food.
Name of the user,
but then at the real time when they
trying to on the UI when you're trying to
show the history of all the others,
then in the back it will try to fetch the
user's first name,
last name from user management from FBN.
And if the profile got deleted,
then you would cannot return that
information,
so it will break the other other history,
but anyway.
JP,
and we agree this is not a good use case
for the reason to keep the user profile
in the record.
So there will be some changes.
So I don't know how,
we haven't talked about that yet,
but we realize there is a dependency,
but it's not a good use case.
So in the future, we have to change.
how do we return the user information for
all the trial for the transactional
history. But then at the same time,
it doesn't become a problem to us yet.
It's annoying when you're going through
the user list, you see.
a lot of inactive user.
So one of the way we're trying to do is
we provide that search so people can jump
to the person you're trying to manage for.
And also at the same time,
we were contemplating maybe put some
filter on the top so you can filter by
status or some other things.
So maybe it's the active and inactive
user coexist and also returnable on the
UI,
but just that we want to improve the user
experience at least.
So these are something we've talked about,
but we didn't put it in any.
So, any, any epic, any work yet,
because again,
is not that the scream is not loud enough,
so people can still stand it, so yeah.
Sorry, I think, I think it is,
I know that this is not a problem,
and it's not an issue that we think now,
but I think for these kind of issues,
there are data lifecycle policy that
comes from, you know,
from regulatory or upper
You know, for security team,
someone in the organization, for example,
in banking,
if you have an account two years,
you know, five years ago,
they still keep it,
but it's under archive mode, and you know,
you need, if you need to access it,
Yeah.
you need to go.
fill a form and then maybe after hours
they provide you. But after five years,
it goes to the deletion model and no more.
I think 10 years, not five years.
But I think for these kind of activities,
we need to have a data lifecycle policy
from bank or redefine it by ourselves,
something like that.
There's, I would say, to add to that,
so you at the basis of it,
you do need that data lifecycle policy
for the user profiles,
and then on top of it, like,
and then like what makes sense from a
retention perspective,
and then on top of it would be just the
actual function itself is when does it
become a thing, it.
it will probably become more relevant as
you actually expose this to external
firms.
And now firms are managing and they're
saying,
I want to represent that this user is
truly no longer part of the organization.
I can tell, like I look at this list,
these are all the N BNI end users.
I don't know who's left.
I don't know who's still here.
I can't tell from here, right?
If they've left, I should delete them.
Not to say delete as in delete and purge,
I'm just saying delete and archive, right?
I don't need to purge it.
Purging is based on, like you said,
the data policy, retention policy.
But I think...
Once you give this a version of this to a
firm,
and then the firm needs to start
reasonably managing their users against
their lifecycle policies and their user
provisioning and deprovisioning policies,
they're going to want to see that people
who don't belong to my firm,
they shouldn't be an entry even.
Like I should just delete their profile.
Right. I don't want to see them at all.
I think you're going to get that maybe
later in the year when you get to
self-serve.
So there's that demand part of it.
And yeah,
there's this intrinsic kind of how do you
manage the retention?
We don't have a policy for that today.
A lot of things on the platform just live
on forever right now.
Because still pretty new,
we can get away with it and storage is
cheap and tools are internal.
Ha ha ha.
Yeah.
But yeah, this is this is not great.
What else in the user lifecycle
management? So,
so you've played around with this as well.
So we talk,
I think we even talked a little bit
yesterday,
but I would I would maybe encourage Ali
based on the conversation yesterday
around kind of the upload is talk to
Radhika,
but like in the interview Radhika about
all of the spreadsheet issues we've had
in the past.
Mhm.
around this from kind of the initial
launch through to every time you launch a
feature, she needs to use this tool.
So it's good to just get her very
specific perspective and all the things
that go horribly sideways when we use
this tool.
That'll give you both a perspective of
the upload functionality and limitations.
I think she knows better than Candi and I
put together.
And it also gives you that why do we hate
spreadsheets perspective.
Mhm.
So I'm gonna leave you with that with
that task.
Yeah, sorry,
you said every time we launch a feature,
she has to she has to upload users again,
something like that.
Yeah.
Yeah,
so because this upload tool is actually
user updates, right? So Candi,
correct me if we're wrong,
Yeah.
it facilitates creation and updates,
create and updates.
Okay,
so it means that she has to update the
features column, and so why she,
why R&
D team didn't take the responsibility for
doing it? It's, I think it's an upper.
Which?
It's a task on their side.
Mm.
For, for which we?
No, I think it depends.
So when we launch a new feature, yes,
s s team would generate and update the
user packages. And then if there's an,
so let's say I add the CRS factor to.
to one user package.
So they will update the JSON and update
the user package.
And if there's any existing user
currently being assigned to that user
package,
now there's a new feature and then add to
that user assignment.
But then the default is it yes or no.
then is something is also controlled by
the user package upload.
So it will align that.
But another thing is,
because usually when we launch it,
there will be a rollout plan managed by
Radhika team. So maybe they would say.
Now,
this is globally available to like 5 or 6
user packages. And then they have a plan,
we will turn it on for five firms this
week and then another 10 firms next week.
So that's the time they would use the
bulk updates to manipulate.
Turning on and off per firm per user.
So,
it's still the mandate because they have
to control the rollout.
If it's a one-time update,
like it's so let's say system system
health alert,
we want everyone to get it on the at the
same time at launch, then the.
Package update can take care of setting,
setting it, turn it on for everyone.
So there's no intervention of activation
team, but if they want to roll it out.
According to some schedule,
they will use the bulk updates to
manipulate the offering. Yeah.
So,
this two different approach depending on
the role plan, yeah.
Did that answer? Yeah.
Does it make sense?
Yeah, okay.
Yeah, I understand. But yeah, that's,
I didn't know about the priority of the
rollout plan.
It seems that there is a policy firm by
firm, which, yeah, I wasn't aware. Okay.
Yeah, maybe, because again, this kind of,
this will impact your understanding of,
I guess, the feature life cycle,
the toggling and all of that stuff as
well is,
we don't do this for all features,
but generally, if it comes from this team,
it's usually a major feature.
When you go and launch major features,
different firms use different
use things in different ways and
sometimes firms will even take up our
feature and we discussed this before,
right?
And so depending on that segmentation,
we try not to roll out everything at once
because we probably end up getting a lot
of confusion and noise,
especially from our bigger firms.
So we tend to stage it. So
Good example and looking at,
because I was trying to pull up,
when did we do this last?
I think GIC was probably a really good
example of that. You know, with GICs,
just even simple things like our large
IBs have approvals and intervention
thresholds that are different.
Our PMs don't have that at all.
So it's actually easy to flip the switch
on for PMs who are actually all very low
volume as well for GICs.
We can give them two weeks notice,
then we turn it on.
They don't say anything, they're good.
We never hear it from them again.
That's actually what happened.
But for the large brokers,
there's two training sessions,
maybe another one ahead of time.
This is how it works for head office.
This is how it works for advisors.
We segment that communication within the
firm as well.
We give them plenty of lead time because
these large brokers, again, remember,
large brokers, they're decentralized,
lots and lots of branches all over the
country, right?
So they need lead time to pre-communicate
these features to their advisors,
and the communication should come from
them because they're head office.
So we train them, they train their staff,
their staff does the communication,
we do a test,
does everybody at head office understands
how this feature works, and then we go.
So to do all of that at once and then
launch in one day is not viable for us,
like for us, like for the firms, we can,
you can say, oh yeah,
you can do all those activities,
line them up, and we go.
And so three or four phases at minimum,
usually for major features.
And so you're going to be updating a
batch of firms 1 by 1 here to say,
I'm going to enable GICs, right?
I'm going to go into firm settings.
I'm going to go to each firm because we
don't have, remember,
we don't have bulk firm upload.
This is what Radhika was talking about
yesterday. If I want to.
Yeah.
enable a firm, enable a feature,
I have to go into each PM one by one,
and I'm going to have to check the firm
settings and enable GICs in here.
Once I'm done that, though,
then I can use the upload spreadsheet and
say, okay, for all these users,
I can see that in their profile,
they should be getting,
or this is a core product,
they should be getting it by default.
I'm going to take all the users from
these firms now and I'm going to like
activate the activate it on the firms
behalf.
I'm going to do it all at once and I'm
going to do it the day before the night
before we launch.
So they come in the next morning,
it's already there.
But I need to do that like four or five
times for every major launch.
Yeah, and also some firms,
especially some bigger firms,
they only want to turn it on for a couple
of users in their own firm to just maybe
get some idea before they broadcast it to
everyone.
So that's why you turn on the firm
setting.
But at the same time, you switch,
you change the user setting for only a
couple of users to manage the DE.
Yeah,
so usually is a fairly custom made based
on the negotiation with the firm. Yeah,
and yeah, and yeah, some other criteria.
Sorry,
I understand just one glitch is here that
I see that we can turn it on on the firm
settings level and user packages will
inherit it from the firm settings.
The thing is that it's a matter of the
toggle on and off for users.
Mhm.
When you go for a major feature,
go to pre-training,
having a communication rollout.
So it can be here exactly.
It can be here and it can be unticked.
And then after communication and training,
it can be to the...
from security store to make it on and off
for their users. No need to eradicate.
Correct. Well, in the future,
that's where you want to be. But remember,
firm security stewards don't have access
to this today,
so we have to do it on their behalf.
Oh, okay, sorry. Okay.
No, good question. Yeah.
And that could be a model and it depends
on what it is, right, Ali? Like, so,
like I said, if it depends on the feature,
Yeah.
right?
If it's a value add or if it's something
OK.
that we don't really care about, like,
depends on what it is. We might say, yeah,
we'll allow the firm security steer to
make that decision on the behalf of their
users.
we don't have to deal with any of that
admin. That's actually ideal,
but there are times where we say, no,
we're gonna shove this in their firms'
faces,
or we're migrating them from legacy to
new. So instead of saying, okay,
you're set up on net rep,
now you get trading,
I'm gonna make you reconfigure all the
users yourself in trading. No,
you know what, as a...
As a good service offering and a good
client experience approach,
we will help migrate you.
That's a much better way to engage with
clients,
especially because we know what you have,
I understand.
so why are we making you do it all over
again? So,
that would be kind of like the discussion.
Yeah.
But either way,
the goal for the platform is to be able
to facilitate one way or the other, right?
So that we have that choice.
So BNI might make the call,
we'll push it out to everybody. Okay,
we have got a bulk upload tool.
We can do that.
We can set everybody all at once.
We can assist a firm in doing that
Mm.
because some firms are a little bit
slower than others and a little bit more
annoying than others and pedantic than
others. And so we might say,
Okay,
maybe we'll help you set that up because
you have 800 users, right? Like,
it's hard to do that,
but I'll do the bulk for you.
Or we have small firms where you just
don't care and you're like, yeah,
you go figure it out yourself.
You have 10 users anyway. Like,
it doesn't matter. Yeah, and yeah.
Yeah, good.
Good question, though. Yeah, yeah.
Thank you.
I hope you're I hope you're kind of
building your backlog from here.
There's a lot of stuff that we missed in
the first pass.
That's why, that's why I.
Okay.
So where were we?
We were here on user life cycle,
so delete is gray. We talked about that.
I think I put bulk in here somewhere too.
Access request management, that's UAM,
so you know what that is.
I didn't gray it out because you're going
to ship it.
Bulk user actions is what we just talked
about, the user create or updates.
You already saw the user audit trail too.
I think you were poking around in that.
So I don't think we need to get too much
into that.
Persis of it really is for user
investigations, right? Like it's,
you just got to know what happened at
some point. Why did this user have access?
Why didn't they have access?
What happened? Who configured it?
Like maybe somebody fat fingered.
Maybe it's fraud. Like, you know, right?
Like.
So you just need the ability to do that.
Candi, I think we're in a, like, is it,
are we in a good place with the user
audit trail?
Because I know we had some bugs and it
does support some things and doesn't
support other things.
I don't know if you can pull it up and we
can take a look at it maybe.
Yeah, I just,
I think user audit trail is the scope
today is limited to FBN.
And as a global audit trail,
I think we have restriction. For example,
what the user has done when they have
opened ordering application,
when they have opened trading application.
We are restricted.
To track the user activities into
different sectors, and I know that,
for if we want to add the scope to other
things,
we need to have a good integration,
but yeah, today...
Our scope is limited to FBN.
It's a good question. We,
it didn't go that,
it's not a global view of all user
actions. It's certainly not,
because that's not the intent of the user
audit trail. So you're right,
it is limited to FBN UM. Candi,
I'm actually trying to find the PR for
Mhm.
this. Maybe we didn't create one. Well,
maybe it's this.
That is an epic is in a Hub.
Okay.
It was one piece to add was the primary
Ohh yeah.
problem we were trying to solve,
and you can look at Candi's features here
when you have a chance,
was to understand access related changes
for when we have a security audit or when
we need to do a security investigation.
Why did the user have access to something?
That was the main purpose of it. So it is,
that's the reason why it's confined to
firming user management.
And it was a pretty urgent use case
because you really couldn't,
like even just day-to-day support
inquiries, right?
Like they can't tell who did what to that
profile.
You kind of had to pull the logs for that
to make sense of it. Like you.
I don't know if you remember the trading
incident I talked about where yesterday
where, you know,
Industrial Alliance got access to the
orders module. Was that a user, like,
was that an access assignment issue?
Yeah.
Was that a packaging issue? When we,
when the incident initiated,
the first thing was, oh,
did we miss assign the user?
with permissions.
We couldn't look that up, right?
We just had to go into the profile.
Is it there? Is it not?
It's pretty binary. We can't say, okay,
did somebody actually do something about
it?
So that was that was not a good that was
not a good way to troubleshoot.
Veryan had to one of our developers had
to pull the logs to see what actually
happened.
And it turns out nobody made any profile
changes to that user, right?
Or no, it was, I think,
the bulk user update is something weird
to the user. Sorry, no, that was GIC.
We had an incident for GIC as well.
And so that was this,
this feature was born out of the security
investigations that we had to do where it
was not supported at all.
It exists in R2 today.
I think to some extent it exists in
Secure Zone today,
if it didn't exist at all for Compass,
so we had to add it.
Now we can go in and say, okay,
did the person,
did we update the feature access,
which is typically the most reoccurring
question that you get,
or did we give this person extra R code
access, which is the second,
probably second most question,
often frequent question that you get.
So it was very specific to that and
surround access changing.
Mm.
And probably the most important one,
'cause you know, so...
We typically have a question because
there's a security,
like there's a breach or there is a
potential breach.
That's when you get those questions.
So we wanted to provide support for that.
And in a timely way,
you don't want to leave,
Yeah.
you don't want to spend hours trying to
troll through logs,
you need to know right away.
Is there a need for a global user actions
type audit trail?
Use cases for that, honestly,
it's nice to have,
but I don't even think it's high on the
list at all. It's just simply because,
again,
if you're trying to trace a user action,
it's typically coming from an unexpected
transaction somewhere. And you kind of go,
oh, why did this thing move?
didn't get moved out of a client's
account or something like that. It's not,
it's never kind of very specific to, oh,
did this employee do that action? It's no,
what happened to that account? Who did it,
right?
And so the orientation is more on the
transactional side. Typically,
I'm going to go into servicing.
I want to see, oh,
did that payment go out?
right?
Or did somebody **** ** the number in
there and now it's not what I expected?
And then you go, okay, who did that?
Because it clearly is a mistake.
And then you go and smack the employee in
the head, right? But it's never,
like the 360 probably again comes from if
you had fraud. And now can you tell me?
what this employee did or didn't do
across the platform, you will,
that's really the core use case of that
360 view is what did you actually do,
right? Or for, you know, for us,
product team usage analytics,
that's a totally separate thing,
but that's for adoption monitoring,
Yeah.
all that fun stuff, right? We.
We have been getting more fraud incidents,
for sure, in the last few years,
but you're talking maybe like one or two
a year. We've also had access breaches.
It's happening more often.
Firms are getting targeted for phishing
attacks and for external fraud.
And so it might
Mhm.
actually become a use case?
You don't know. But again,
typically it's the orientation is around
the transaction.
As long as a firm has like that global
view of all the transactions within the
firm,
that's probably the entry point for the
investigation,
unless they're really specifically
focused on a particular employee.
But even then, they're going to go, okay,
this employee plays trades and they kind
of move money out and
funnel into like some offshore thing or
whatever, right? Like.
Yeah.
So you never know, never say never,
but that's the reason why it's not high
on the list is maybe we do investigation
once, twice a year,
No.
talk to Jonathan Seguin, right?
When you get a chance to see what the
landscape is like today,
he can tell you all about, you know,
like our security posture and the sort of
the current risks that we have and the
risk lens we have at the bank for it or
at an BNI.
That would be a really good perspective.
I don't know if you've met him yet,
but it would give you an understanding of
the magnitude of the risk. And Kevin,
I would strongly encourage you to share
at the NBI Risk Committee some of the
reporting to Ali on that,
because there is a huge section on
operational risk and cybersecurity risk
that as a business we track and we report
on every quarter from our risk team.
Yeah, I'll bring that back.
I don't know when the next one is.
I think it's coming up,
but I will bring that back. Yeah.
There should be one coming up, I think,
in October.
Yeah.
I think Ed proved it.
Yeah.
Okay, so that's,
I wasn't going to get into user audit
trail, but I guess we did.
Final piece on the lifecycle,
so if you think BAU, user creation,
and what have you not, at the end of it,
Use that as.
continuous monitoring is important. Again,
it's managing risk,
it's managing access risk,
managing security risk, and privacy risk,
and all that fun stuff.
We do have a bank policy to have even our
internal systems and attestation process.
You saw that in the employee SSO.
It's a bank standard.
The reason for having that standard is,
again,
it's just to make sure that you catch,
you know, you catch,
you've got good processes to begin with.
If somebody deports,
Usually, it's related to off-boarding.
If somebody leaves,
you better like deactivate them and then
if you forget,
at least there's a there's a like a like
a safeguard process every quarter for me
to make you look at the other users and
make sure that you are performing that
review.
in case you missed something, right?
So the quarterly cadence comes from that
notion of, you know,
what chances are if you miss something,
risk period is maybe once a quarter,
right? Like if you leave somebody for two,
three months,
maybe it's not as big a deal as if you
kind of left them kind of inactive or
active for like a year. So
Every quarter, we say at minimum,
go through the process,
review all your users,
make sure that you deactivate users who
are no longer at your firm,
or if they have too much access,
re-rectify that access.
And we actually make the firms kind of,
well,
we encourage strongly for the firms to do
that review, and we provide the data
like the user data to our systems for the
firms to review. Today,
It's kind of this kind of this color
because we do have a legacy process run
by the data team that drops files for the
firm to look at their user accesses every
quarter.
Our firms quite actually surprisingly
relies on that data also to see who their
user list is, because once again,
They don't have access to Compass.
They don't know who they registered on
Compass.
That's the only source of truth they have
is getting that file and looking out
who's listed under the CX list.
In some cases, for the PMs,
they don't even get this sort of like
this security steer review.
They don't even get that in R2.
in legacy.
And so the attestation file is actually
also a user list for some of our firms,
and they get that updated once a quarter,
which is really not great. So,
but that's kind of meeting the minimum
requirements of please review your users.
We don't tend to,
because they signed an agreement with us
at the more kind of, you know,
the kind of service level,
at this more services level to govern the
global relationship that they have with
NDIN. And in the services agreement,
they do have accountability over,
you know, the management of their assets,
the systems and who they provision it to.
And so it is acknowledged that they do
own these users,
they do need to review it.
So we today don't collect like
acknowledgement or anything like that.
We just kind of expect them to do the
review.
That's that actually somewhat needs to
change because that's not great posture.
We don't, there's no like,
there's no way for us to tell if they
even do the attestation or not.
We meet some firms and we know they don't.
We meet other firms and we know they do.
And they sort of like those files are
like their viable, right?
And some firms are very negligent and so
they don't have good processes and
control.
So they just kind of toss it to the side
and they forget about it.
So the current state, I would say,
of user attestations today,
it's implemented such that it is very
minimum and it is very hands-off.
And part of.
the kind of the compass offering and
getting that attestation process improved
is something that we actually looked at
this year. So we said earlier this year,
although we'll maybe get it more into a
separate session of why we didn't pull
the trigger on that feature,
because it's actually built, Ali,
I think it's a new ET or production or
somewhere.
I don't know where it is,
but we kind of said, you know what,
if we're going to start,
if you're going to give data to users,
number one,
the goal is continuous monitoring.
Having quarterly files is not good.
By the way,
we have a user list in Compass.
We just need to figure out a way to
externalize it, right?
We have our view here, you know.
There's maybe a view that we can give to
our firms because it's the same list.
It's just that some things on here don't
work quite well. Our firms might not,
like they won't,
we don't train them on what this means,
roles, right?
Like it's an internal concept.
We don't ever want them to know what that
means because, you know, manage all,
like what is that to a firm?
So they wouldn't really understand.
I think, I don't know, Candi,
if there's like usability stuff or
statuses aren't totally up to date or I
don't know what's there might be some
stuff.
No,
but that is all going back to user UAM,
because UAM, one of the epics,
we have to modify or externalize the user
monitoring exactly this page,
and then we have to make it more friendly
for external user.
And there's also,
if you open up the details,
it should somehow somehow align to the
form, Ali. So then users can just,
to Owen's form, right?
And then user can make the request,
make the change request from here.
So,
that's also one of the one of the Monday
of the UAM, if we can get to that.
If, well,
you guys will have to get to that at some
point because the, again,
the target vision is like, it's, I mean,
Yeah.
it's industry standard for the last like
20 years, right? You buy a SAS,
you get access to your users in the SAS,
you're thinking, Ali, why don't you even,
why don't you guys even have this already,
right? Like, so.
really first principles things. Again,
it's just a matter of shortcuts,
prioritizations,
these files that exist before,
how do you retrofit a new system into
that?
How do you get the firms to migrate over?
Remember,
those attestation files have users across
all the different systems.
You now know that it's not just Compass,
but it's R2, it's Secured Zone,
it's NetRep, it's OSS.
right? It increases.
Those users don't exist on Compass.
So how do you do an attestation process
for those?
You got to bring them into Compass first.
So there was just kind of prerequisites,
limitations, prioritization, again,
where we couldn't get far enough to hit
the vision of giving access to users so
they can see what their users have,
the link system accesses that they have.
They have the feature access within those
systems live, so you can get it anytime.
And by the way, if you can get it anytime,
then maybe we're not relying on a
quarterly file.
You can just deactivate them here when
they leave the organization, right?
You don't need to kind of go through that.
Most of our perm.
firms prefer that.
They all have their offboarding processes.
They offboard onto their own systems.
They can't do it in Compass, right? So,
self-serve and self-serve deactivation,
self-serve password resets, right?
Like on behalf of their users, to like,
you know, password resets, to FA resets.
All of this stuff is really basic.
We actually don't provide this for firms.
And this actually is a really good basis
if you do.
to enhance the attestation process to
make it continuous.
And then every quarter, then it's,
can you acknowledge that you're staying
on top of your users? Instead of,
here's a file, go through it all,
read it all, do it once a quarter.
Maybe you forget, maybe you don't.
The attestation more becomes an
acknowledgement of,
Yeah.
are you sure that this is still all the
users that should be active in your
system?
So it fundamentally actually changes the
whole flow, right?
And all the stuff that we send out to our
firms, we're not sending us,
we're not sending stuff out anymore.
Yeah, yeah, I agree. Actually,
one of the things that during last couple
of meetings we had is one of the goals
always you say is self-serve.
So I think you also mentioned that after
multi-firm, we have to,
Yeah.
after implementing multi-firm,
we have to go through this path to make
it more self-serve.
And I think maybe we can start it earlier.
For example, do A, B, and test, you know,
Mhm.
make this available for some of smart
firms.
or definitely we know which ones are
smarter and make this form available for
Yes, ma'am.
them.
And then we'll see what's the behavior.
Because right now that I'm thinking is
that the feedbacks that we receive from
them will also enhance the form that we
were talking yesterday.
About the future registry,
I know that this is totally internal,
Yeah.
but it also enhanced that what users
expect, maybe, maybe they don't,
they don't think.
too complex,
they just want simple things in hand and
to go, you know,
do their operational business as usual.
But yeah,
I think maybe we can make it available,
A&B test,
like for some of smart users,
some of smart firms.
and then see what they do.
And on top of that,
I think maybe it's a good time,
we should talk about it,
to use AIML to provide the recommendation
about the user activities for the
attestation purpose. For example,
take the user activities last 90 days and
Yeah.
provide, okay,
this user didn't have any activity.
It's a candidate for you to review.
You know,
these are the things that we can do later.
Yeah.
Exactly, exactly. And in fact, the debate,
the debate you're going to have is
because how are you going to...
You know,
does it make sense for you to launch UAM
without at least presenting back the user
list?
Right? How do you like,
does that work for a user in completing
Thank you.
their flow?
And then how do you modify a user without
this, without a user list?
And how do you pull up the user record?
So you might actually have to package
that in any way.
Yeah.
into the UAM before you get to multi-firm.
Because by the time you get to multi-firm,
you'll see that actually there's
additional configurations now that are
going to be even more complicated to
track.
Imagine a security steward with those
crazy files that they get today.
So they'll get a screen,
they get the crazy files.
And now they have to keep track of which
users are actual parent users that are
assigned to the parent firm.
and which ones only exist within my firms.
If I look at a flat list,
it's a little bit hard.
And then how do I request for access to
that is a little bit hard.
So like the bigger firms,
you'll see in some of the client
interviews we did,
like they have whole spreadsheets and
like Word documents and all this crazy
**** to just keep track of our
environment today.
you'll see that and then we're going to
add to that, right? So I think, like,
I'm not sure I'm going to get to that
debate with you guys because you need to
estimate and size it.
But I do think that there needs to do a
way to kind of come back to the user
monitoring at minimum.
So then your decision there is, okay,
I need to present a user list.
How do like how do I best present it and
not not overkill it?
And if you're already presenting the user
list,
do you then also throw in the
deactivation and maybe the 2FA and
password reset so that those calls don't
come to us anymore?
Right, it's not a separate request, like,
like is it worth doing,
Yeah.
especially because those things,
as Candi and JP and Owen believe,
are like we say,
we often think things are simple and they
become this big project,
which is exactly what the UAR is.
But I think those things are actually
really simple because they actually exist
for us today. It's in production. Like,
I can go and deactivate a user today.
Right. So something to think about.
I had originally scoped it in,
but it's going to be way beyond Q4 at
this stage.
We, I, I've prepared the description,
the epic description, and I, I think,
yeah,
the minimum we have to provide the user
list, the user detail,
and I also flow in the reset password
with that to FA, as you mentioned,
is something we can offload and also.
building the foundation for the
self-serve user management. But again,
I'm worried about the timeline. Yeah,
just that I don't know how much we can do
and everything's prioritized.
So I think the monitoring would be
secondary to if you have to create a farm
first, you know,
build up the piece out first.
So a lot of things has to be done before
we can tackle on this one.
But it's kind of in the pipeline.
We have it on the user story map,
and I put in some detail,
what I think would be appropriate for the
epic scope. So we can get back to that.
Yeah. I think these are all good points,
but then we have to go back to the
discovery and see how much we can do and
by when. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's worth exploring. Remember,
you are only tied to your only dependency
for multi-firm is trading right for now,
and to obviously to get the plug out of
R2,
but mainly is it's to support the trading
launch. So,
as long as you are aligned with Stan on
when that GA date
is and have a work back plan,
which he's not for sure going to launch
until at least the end of Q2,
which is like May.
For sure,
that that would be at least my advice to
him. We go sooner than that,
he's gonna start to see performance
issues that he don't know,
he this his team doesn't know how to fix,
right? So, if you think like,
and the reason for trading is most of the
sub-advisor use cases and the like the
parent firm use cases,
'cause they're transactional, right? Like,
especially the sub-advisors.
So advisors really only come onto the
platform to trade.
So right now you can get away with it
because they can have multi-firm and net
rep. They're fine.
But you can't migrate those users into CX
without implementing the ability for me
that exists in one firm to trade for
another firm.
Right? Like that's the biggest limitation.
So as long as you line it up to DA for
training,
Stan can pick users in beta and pilot
that don't have sub-advisors.
He can do that because it's always a
small set of firms.
When we have plenty of firms to go around,
he doesn't have to pick firms that have
sub-advisory accesses, right,
for other firms, right?
So that's your,
like your drop dead for completing the
bill.
I would say it's going to be around May.
So you have time to work backwards to say
how big is multi-firm and all the changes
that are required.
And then you cap that and reserve
capacity for that.
Now you're going to say, okay,
how much time do I have in Q1?
to deal with self-serve.
That's how I would kind of figure it out.
We can, we can look at the, don't worry,
you don't have to remember all of this,
because we're going to go back at the end
of our discussion and look at the roadmap
itself. OK.
But Kevin, you got that right?
I have a question.
Maybe it's related to regulatory,
but in terms of sub-advisor or
parent-child users,
when you say a sub-advisor need to log in
and do the trade,
Can we can a sub advisor impersonate with
the advisor account and do the trade and
and we don't need to create an individual
account for sub advisor?
Because I think with this activity,
it's a new event.
We also can track when the impersonate
that user,
what the impersonated user has done.
And no need to create all these user
activities.
Or, you know,
user information or create user for self
advisor.
So,
I'm going to end that with another side
I don't know.
quest for you, Ali. So, it is somewhat,
I think it is documented in the
multi-firm PRD,
the sub-advisor relationship,
and you can also ask copilot if, like,
if you ask kind of like the regulatory
boundaries that govern the relationship,
you can ask it that,
and it should give you,
because that's what I did, right? Like,
I was like, you know,
just give me everything you know on the
internet about this and put it on the
page. That question should answer itself.
I would do that first,
and then we can debrief when we get to
the multi-firm epic.
Okay, okay, I'll find that.
Yeah, like,
but but do you take the time to look at
the like the regulatory compliance
requirements around this and what what
type of relationship is it right between
between firms?
I think I did pay some of it into the PRD
as well. Like, like, you know, there's,
I think it's not in the main PRD,
but I think in the supplementary pages,
there's, I think there's some stuff.
that I wrote.
So advisory in Canadian wealth management.
So.
Oh.
There you go. Actually,
I think Stan started this and then I
threw in some more stuff.
Yeah,
so underfirm relationships and then do do
Okay.
some internet digging as well.
Sure, sure. Thank you. Thank you.
And by the way,
when it when it comes to banking
regulation,
there's always there's always reference
to an actual regulatory requirement.
Like BNI 3113.
Great, thank you.
Good question, good question.
I think that's it for user lifecycle
management, to be honest with you.
Like I said,
this CX stuff is not self-serve in R2.
I think for better clarity onto what's
available today, Ali,
it is different system to system.
I think it's worth spending some time.
Candi, I think you've documented.
those flows of what an IB versus a PM can
do and why.
IVs are self-serve and PMs are not in
legacy today.
Remember the shared broker code and the
versus the that's the main reason.
Yeah.
But maybe take another take another look
at it if you haven't looked at it into
detail yet on the user access management
capabilities of legacy.
So you know that what you know what we're
transitioning into.
for those firms.
So, take a deep dive on that,
take a look at Super Seguin.
Mhm.
So, what, what data documents?
Sorry?
Did I document something?
I don't know. I think so. I'm not sure,
but I think Ali needs a walk.
It's not in here, what do you mean?
You want another recorded session, Candi,
but can you walk him through Compass
Legacy,
feature a firm security portal security
steward, portal super steward?
I can never tell the difference between
the two. You know, yeah,
what our internal teams have, you know,
Oh, okay, okay.
how the PM flow is for access life cycle,
what the IB flow is for access life cycle.
I'm pretty sure we docked.
Oh, okay, okay. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
that sounds familiar. Yeah, yeah. Okay,
Remember the, yeah, yeah,
to get more familiar with it, it's yeah,
okay, cool.
just to pick up on the legacy.
Funky things.
Yeah.
that we're trying to resolve.
I, sorry,
I need to bring up this question because
earlier today we had a meeting with Kevin
as well,
and he also mentioned we need to
decommission or to, you know,
as soon as possible.
I think I already asked this question
from you.
Penny the other day about this, and...
When we say decommission,
what does that mean?
Because decommission from understanding
is that we make a application end of live
and transition to a new version, okay?
But...
Yes, yeah.
Well, for example,
when we say decommission R2 by 2027,
it means that all the users who were
supposed to log into R2 are going to log
into CX from, for example,
let's say end of.
September 2027.
Is it is it the right definition or is it
something else?
No, your first definition is accurate.
We have to power down the servers and the
databases.
Mhm.
So it's more than redirecting login,
because we actually already did that.
Users are logging into Compass,
new Compass today to get access to Legacy
Compass, right?
So you've already done that,
but you're still in Legacy Compass
because there's still features in there.
And one of those features, by the way,
is user management, right?
And Legacy Compass to manage legacy users,
which...
Doesn't even make any sense anymore,
right? So, yeah, like, so what would,
you know,
what would you need to do to power down
those servers? Well,
that code's not gonna run anymore.
Yeah.
Yeah, you need to get rid of it.
But when we say power down those servers,
still there are users that are...
Acting there because they log into CX and
click on log compass legacy and then
redirect there. So it's like a loop.
I don't understand because.
Yeah.
Yeah, is it? Like,
because if you're shutting down,
if you're shutting down the app, well,
they should,
they can't get access to that app anymore
when you shut it down.
And why we don't define a date to shut it
down?
You do, it's end of 2027.
It's October 31st, 2027.
You have to shut it down, yeah, yeah,
yeah.
Oh, okay. Oh.
So in the meantime, Ali,
we're working desperately,
quickly to redo all the stuff that's in
there and rewrite it and stick it into CX.
So the goal by the end, as Penny said,
is there's no activity in the server in
the back end anymore.
None of the services are being used
anymore.
We remove access to redirect into the old
platform and everything that they used to
be able to do there,
they can do in CX today.
And is there any written project plan or
a plan to say, okay, for example,
80% progress is achieved, 20% is remain,
and what is 20% area?
Do we have something written or?
or it's in the mind of different people.
Well,
you're looking at the guy who owns the
initiative.
Ohh, OK.
It's not in the mind, it's in a hub.
You should be able to track it in a hub.
Yeah.
Kevin should be able to show you the full
scope of all the R2 features. Actually,
Yeah.
I'm not going to go into it.
You can ask Kevin.
Yeah,
we can just sit down and take a look at
OK.
it.
There is a roadmap around all the
development that needs to be done and
everything that needs to be done.
We're actively working on it as we speak.
And we do have a sequence of events that
we were trying to work towards right now.
And it is all in aha.
Okay.
Pull.
49% according to your all of your latest
updates. We're at 49%.
Mm-hmm.
Based on all the features and ethics that
are now in the roadmap tagged against
R2Dcom, that's where you guys are.
It could be inaccurate because some
people don't like to update stuff or some
people's team members don't like to
update stuff.
So this number might not be accurate
because of that.
But you're good in firm and user
management,
not only because we cleaned it all up and
Candi and I actually maintained the board.
So, Kevin, well, not you specifically,
but I think you gotta get some people's
**** together. Um, right.
Yes.
It should be fairly accurate now,
to be honest with you, but yeah,
Yeah, I think it is.
I think this feels about right.
there are, yeah.
Yeah.
This feels about right.
And then each product line contributes to
that initiative, right?
So the only thing I didn't check is, like,
I don't,
I'm not totally sure if I actually,
I think I did actually do a pass and
still associated all the features to the
initiative tab.
I think I did that for you,
but I'm not sure.
So maybe double check that in your
measure if you want that as a reporting.
Yeah, double check it.
But Ali, I think.
Yeah, so Ali, I don't.
So, go ahead, Penny.
No.
Well, I was just going to say,
so in our little team meeting today,
you heard Evert list off a whole bunch of
stuff that she's working on.
Every single one of those is a line item
under that initiative.
Okay.
So for you, Ali,
you do need to be aware of the platform
management components in legacy that
contributes to the decommissioning.
You do need to know that.
Your.
which you should be able to tell,
by the way. Number one,
through an audit of the legacy platform,
so you can get very familiar with it,
but anything that's actually tagged with
R2Dcon,
I don't know what's doing stupid ****.
Okay,
anything that's tagged to R2Dcon that can
AI tag on your board,
like if you see that.
That's a legacy feature in Compass,
in Legacy Compass. Yeah, yeah,
I think I think we typed most things.
I'm not sure how complete it is.
We can do another path, but...
you should be able to just filter by that.
So as long as you're aware of how you're
contributing to that initiative,
you should be good.
Yeah, Penny,
I think we we taking care of the
Great, okay.
authentication. So,
UAM pretty much is the focus.
We contributing to the out to
decommissioning,
but then the deep links and the
navigation are controlled by are under.
different PMs, right?
The vendor has some and then I think
Yeah, we don't,
we don't care about just just platform
Evert has some. So those, yeah, exactly.
management capability legacy is what you
need to move out, and sorry,
Yeah.
it's not the ethics.
I think we look at the features, Ali. So,
in the feature view,
the like where you see the R2D column,
those are those are the R2 features that
need to move out.
And in your special case,
because the model sucks so, so much,
as you see now with all our problems,
even with the compatibility with legacy
and how the legacy system is set up,
you're probably on a slightly different
track to your peers, where you know,
Evert, Devendra,
they're really just trying to, you know,
especially for Evert and even some of
Ray's team.
They're really just trying to lift and
shift and get the features out as quickly
as possible. But for platform management,
you've got to onboard everything into the
right model. So you are going to have,
you are going to enhance it.
That's why we're spending so much time in
UAM. Yes, you know,
there is a request process and legacy
today, but it really doesn't work.
It's horrendous. It's not understandable.
It misses stuff. So.
Your path is to make sure that platform
management in CX works, you know,
as best as possible because it's
fundamental to managing all these
features,
so you don't really want to screw it up.
We already screwed it up enough,
so we don't want to screw it up more.
In God.
Okay.
I don't think, I don't think so. Like,
I don't think we need to,
I'm looking at time,
we have 8 minutes left.
I don't think I want to spend time here
because this should be the most visible
and most straightforward feature for you,
right? Like,
it's once you have the feature,
once you have the platform configured,
once you're able to create kind of firm
assignments, user assignments,
and manage the lifecycle of that.
then people just need to get access to
the platform.
That's what this pillar is about.
And so platform access capabilities is
you log in, you do your 2FA, you know,
and then the platform doesn't stuff from
session management. Ideally,
probably shouldn't sit here and this
should sit over there. This is an old map.
You can change it if you like. You know,
platform manages authentication and
authorization,
and then there's some profile management
stuff, which
To me,
it's actually really platform experience,
not platform management,
but nobody's looking after this *******
child, so you get to keep it for now.
But setting up, you know,
user settings against the user profile,
there's a bunch of capabilities there.
If you want more details,
I'm sure somebody can walk you through it,
Candi can walk you through it,
because I want to maybe just finish off
with the external IDP SSO.
piece because this is another one of
those like,
and you know about employee access, right?
You're kind of going through that now,
shadowing candy on it.
So I don't think I want to get into that.
External IDPSSO is a bit of a landmine
because it's really leveraging all of
this stuff that's available and making an
external IDB.
Thanks, Katie.
Having a firm basically bring their own
IDP and connect to Compass.
So this is the opposite of platform
integration is somebody else coming to
Compass through the use of their own IDP.
We have enabled it for two firms today,
Industrial Alliance and Sun Life.
there is a queue of firms that want it,
like Wellington, Altus, Harbor Front.
We stopped selling the external IDP SSO
because there's just fundamental problems
with the operations of this piece.
So maybe very high level what this is, is
A firm has their own IDP, obviously,
because especially these enterprise
clients, they have their own IT,
they have their own technology,
they have their own platforms,
and of course,
they're going to have their own login to
the firm, like, you know,
you need to log into something, right,
to get access to those enterprise
applications that they have.
And more often than not,
they're the ones that want to create a
consolidated view of their user and what
their users have access to.
And so somebody like an industrial
alliance, who,
I don't know if you can see here, I guess,
I don't know, actually,
I don't think we gave you access to
production,
but we'll pull it up because we can see
the attributes for them as well, is.
You know, they have quite a lot of users.
In fact,
not an entirely accurate number because
there's some duplicates,
but they have about 2000 users with us
today.
And those 2000 users also have access to
other applications that they have within
their firm. Obviously,
there's a plethora of those. And so
These firms,
especially when it comes to their desire
to implement effective access control
policies at their firm,
which could be different from ours,
by the way, right?
Because each firm has their own
enterprise standards. Of course,
they're going to have their own access
policies. For them to do that,
more often than not, they do not want
to have separate logins for things that
they purchase off the shelf,
including Compass, which is, you know,
their operational platform, right?
And so they come to us and they said,
well,
can I actually manage my own user
identities and actually pass you over the
representation of that user so that you
can have it in Compass?
It's tied back to the user that I have in
my IDP.
And then I can kind of provision access
here no problem,
but at least that link is there so we can
keep track of what the user has access to.
And I'm managing that user identity on my
side.
I'm not separately configuring an
identity here. Chances are if I do that,
there might be a mismatch.
I might punch in the wrong e-mail address
or something.
We have that same problem too with our
internal systems.
And so in terms of the why firms want it
is
access policy implementation,
managing a control point,
managing one login to access all the
applications that employees should have
access to. That's why we provide SSO,
right? We even do that.
You can SSO into ET, you know,
stuff in-house.
And so they don't want to provision those
users with separate COPRESCOCHEF logins.
More and more firms are doing that
because it is a good way to implement
a centralized access policy.
And then so if they deactivate the user,
I don't have to go into 40 different
systems and deactivate them all.
I delete them in one place and that gets
cascaded, right?
And they should no longer be able to log
into Compass from there.
So that's the premise of it.
That's the background.
I don't think we wrote a PRD for this.
It just kind of happened.
It was a very confusing time because we
were actually trying to launch the
platform as well.
Worst idea on the planet to try to build
this on a moving target.
And that is the reason why we're going to
go through a list of issues with you on
things that don't quite work.
Because we basically hack this in because
the client wants to pay for it.
And they're like, I'm not taking compass.
basically these guys here at Industrial
Alliance,
I'm not taking Compass until you enable
SSO for me.
That's pretty much what they said.
So we said, okay,
let's do it and then we'll charge you for
it. So I guess in terms of how it works,
I don't know, Candi,
if you want to spend 3 minutes on it and
then we can.
Maybe I'm gonna,
can I steal 15 minutes to go through the
issues?
Do you guys mind if we kind of carry it
on for another 15 minutes because I want
to finish this off?
I'm fine. I'm here.
Okay, well, Candi, can I, can I,
because I want to take a...
Yeah, I need a quick break. Yeah,
bathroom break.
Mm.
Yeah.
Sure. Yep.
Any Emmy job for this?
No worries.
Kevin dropped.
Good to go.
Yeah, I'm wondering.
Sorry, yeah, I'm here.
The.
I'm actually wondering if...
Uh, Candi, like, do you prefer walking,
doing the walk through or do you want
someone like an Owen do do the walk
through and how it works?
Do you do you want to go through it?
About the external IDP.
Yeah.
I can go through the onboarding and then
talk about it, but I don't have a profile.
Or do you want the post offices to...
Give a walkthrough.
Now,
I was thinking that might be a good
opportunity for Ali to meet Janet.
Yeah, yeah.
And certainly they have a laundry list of
Hang it with her.
all the problems.
She does,
because that just comes from her.
Yes.
Mhm.
Yeah,
because like otherwise we can give you
the high level, but it's better to see it.
Yeah.
And I think they can show you.
Yash.
Sorry, what's her name? Janet?
Janet, I'll connect the two of you.
Okay.
Yeah,
I think we do that and then that'll buy
some time because Candi,
I think we have some old documentation
lying around.
Do you remember when we initially talked
through that like that that that
provisioning flow with Veryan?
We said what we were going to do and what
we were not going to do and I think
Ishrat had some background as well.
So maybe we pull that all together.
Mhm.
No.
there while Ali goes and investigates
this implementation with Janet.
I think we should.
Mhm.
Yeah,
I can find is in the architecture space.
So that, yeah,
there's some initial design and then part
of it,
but then we have to compare what's
implemented, what's not.
But I think we can tell that, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, I think so. Okay,
so maybe we don't eat until lunch.
I'm going to stop the recording.
Okay.